<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE script SYSTEM "http://barrybecker4.com/schema/script.dtd">
<script author="Barry Becker" date="10/19/2006" name="ludlow" title="The Mansion of Professor Ludlow">
    <scene name="start">
        <description>
***************************************************
********* The Mansion of Professor Ludlow *********
***************************************************
      Adapted from a D&amp;D module by James Ward

You are on a camping trip with a large group of boyscouts.
During a nighttime hike, you get separated from the rest of the group.
You stumble upon a meadow. There in front of you is a large mansion.
You hear an eary plea for help coming from inside.
What do you do?
        </description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Knock on the front door" resultScene="no_response"/>
            <choice description="Open the front door without knocking" resultScene="A.inside_entrance"/>
            <choice description="Scream" resultScene="sky_falls"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="no_response">
        <description>
No one comes to the door and you hear nothing.
A few minutes pass. Still nothing.
        </description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Knock again" resultScene="no_response"/>
            <choice description="Open the front door without knocking" resultScene="A.inside_entrance"/>
            <choice description="Scream" resultScene="sky_falls"/>
            <choice description="Return to the rest of your group" resultScene="quit"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="open_crates">
        <description>
It takes you a really long time, but you finally open and inspect all the crates." +
You find nothing in them except for leaves, dust, and 200 paperclips. ",
        </description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Continue." resultScene="D.crate_room"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="sky_falls">
        <description>The sky falls on you.</description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
    <scene name="stub">
        <description>TBD</description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
    <scene name="quit">
        <description>You go back to the others. They don't believe your story. You enjoy the rest of the camping trip.
        </description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Return to the mansion" resultScene="start"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="A.inside_entrance">
        <description> The double door is unlocked and opens easily.
 The beam of your flashligh reveals an empty hallway with a mirror at the opposite end.
 There are openings that lead to rooms on the left and right.
 The hall has inch-thick red carpeting and walnut-paneled walls.
 The mirror at the end runs from the floor to the twenty-foot-high ceiling
 and covers the forty feet of wall section on that south face of the hall.
        </description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Go through left (east) opening" resultScene="B.rat_room"/>
            <choice description="Go through right (west) opening" resultScene="K.trophyRoom"/>
            <choice description="Tamper with mirror at the end of the hall (to the south). " resultScene="A.mirror"/>
            <choice description="Exit the mansion" resultScene="quit"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="B.rat_room">
        <description>The beams of the flashlights show a room paneled in redstained barn boards with a floor of the same substance.
There is a couch in the northeast corner of the room and an opening out of theroom on the east wall.

There are leaves on the floor, and an old worn out couch in the north east corner.
There is a musty smell to the room, and leaves are littered on the floor.
The couch is an old, dusty, overstuffed relic with several cushions and rips on all parts of it.
The room measures sixty feet east and west and forty feet north and south, if paced out.
There is a door on the east side of the room.
        </description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Inspect the couch." resultScene="B.rat_attack"/>
            <choice description="Sift through the leaves on the floor." resultScene="B.key"/>
            <choice description="Go through the door on the east side." resultScene="C.pink_hallway"/>
            <choice description="Go back to the inside entrance" resultScene="A.inside_entrance"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="C.pink_hallway">
        <description>The beam of your flashlight show a hall with pink walls and a floor of red marble.
The walls have clean squares all over them where pictures were obviously once hung, but are no longer.
The floor has dried leaves littering it. If paced out, the hall is eighty feet long east and west and twenty feet long north and south.
The hall leads to another room at the end.
        </description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Proceed into the room at the end of the hall (east)." resultScene="D.crate_room"/>
            <choice description="Back to previous room (west)" resultScene="B.rat_room"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="D.crate_room">
        <description>
The beam of the flashlight shows a room with gray painted walls and a cement floor.
It is filled with wooden crates and there are leaves all over the room in large piles.
There are 200 empty wooden crates of differing sizes, and the biggest concentration of leaves is in the
southwest corner of the room.
The room measures sixty feet east and west and forty feet north and south and has a side alcove to the
south starting on the east wall that is forty feet long east and west and twenty feet long north and south.
It is here that the concentration of leaves is located. Behind a big crate along the east wall, thirty
feet from the north corner, one finds a door with a normal handle.
        </description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Go through door behind big crate (east)." resultScene="E.gray_storage_room"/>
            <choice description="Look inside all the crates." resultScene="open_crates"/>
            <choice description="Sift through the pile of leaves on the floor." resultScene="D.crate_room_leaves"/>
            <choice description="Back to hallway (west)" resultScene="C.pink_hallway"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="D.crate_room_leaves">
        <description>There are snakes in the leaves. A group of 3 4 foot long rattlesnakes attack.
(HP: 10,8,5; #AT: 1; damage:1-3; AC: 5; SA: Save versus death caused by poison).
        </description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Continue." resultScene="D.crate_room"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="F.oak_room">
        <description>The beams of the flashlights show a room paneled in oak with
an oaken floor that is filled with shelves upon shelves of rocks. From
the door, a set of stairs is visible going up from the south section of
the room.
These shelves are obviously a
geological exhibit of some type, since every sample of rock has a
scientific name on it. Each of the samples weighs about a pound. If
paced out, the room is sixty feet west and east with a partial wall
running north, starting twenty feet from the east wall and extending
forty feet. The room is eighty feet long north and south. On the west
wall in the north corner is a passageway out of the room. Also on that
wall, sixty feet from the north corner, is a doorway. Further down from
this door is a twenty by twenty feet corridor section that ends at the
bottom of the stairs up; on the east wall section by the stairs is
another way out of the room.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Head south and climb the stairs." resultScene="F.stairway"/>
            <choice description="Exit to the east using the opening at the base of the stairs." resultScene="J.Bathroom"/>
            <choice description="Inspect the rocks on the shelves." resultScene="F.rocks"/>
            <choice description="Exit tot the west into the passageway at the north corner of the room" resultScene="G.passageway"/>
            <choice description="Go back to gray storage room." resultScene="E.gray_storage_room"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="E.crazy_man_attacks">
        <description>When you enter the room, you are immediately attacked by an incredibly old man dressed in rags and carrying a butcher knife
(HP: 7; #AT: 1; 0: 1-6; AC: 10; SA:None).
This old man leaps out from behind some of the boxes and surprises you.
He will never follow a retreating group out of the room, but will act dangerously at all other times and will never listen to any type of reason.</description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
    <scene name="E.gray_storage_room">
        <description>The beam of your flashlight shows a room with gray painted walls and a cement floor.
It is filled with boxes and barrels.
There are thirteen barrels of grain alcohol each with the number "50" painted on it.
There are thirteen boxes filled with pairs of white gloves.
A metal chest contains a silver set made to serve eighteen people, four pairs of silver candlesticks,
three huge silver carving knives (like short swords), and eighteen solid silver goblets
(total worth of the silver items is 20,000 silver pieces).
There are thirteen chests filled with books about plants;
thirteen boxes filled with assorted sizes of clay pots;
and ten large crates with mattresses in them.
When paced out, the room is forty feet wide east and west and sixty feet wide north and south.
A door on the east wall is originally hidden by the mattress crates.

        </description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Go through the door on the east side of the room." resultScene="F.oak_room"/>
            <choice description=" Inspect boxes and barrels further." resultScene="E.crazy_man_attacks"/>
            <choice description="Go back to the room with the crates (west)." resultScene="D.crate_room"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="G.passageway">
        <description>The beams of the flashlights show the passageway has
strange objects hanging on its gray painted walls. The floor is of black
marble. There are openings out of the hall from the east and west
ends.
 The hall is lined with hanging medieval weapons: 3 heavy maces, 2 halberds, 3 crossbows
with one bolt each, 3 short swords, 5 huge two-handed swords, 5 dagoers.
4 boar soears. and 3 flails. All of these are easily detachable and have traces of preserving oil on them.
The hall is twenty feet wide, north and south and 100 feet long east and west.

The weapons are all in perfect
condition and do the following damage: Maces-2-7 pts; Halberds-
1-10 pts.; Crossbows-1-4 pts.; Short Swords-1-6 pts.; two-handed
Swords-1-10 pts.; Oaggers-1-4 pts.; Boar Spears-2-7 pts.; and
Flails-2-7 pts.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Travel west along the hallway and open the door at the end." resultScene="H.fur_room"/>
            <choice description=" Go back to the oak storage room." resultScene="F.oak_room"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="F.stairway">
        <description> A creaky old stairway leads up to level 2.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description=" - Put your choice description here -" resultScene="VII.chunksRoom"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="F.rocks">
        <description>All of the valuable minerals in the
rock collection like gold, silver, platinum, and copper, are on shelves
on the south wall in the small corridor created by the dividing northsouth
wall. They will all be on the highest shelves and above the
normal eye level of any scout. There are no crystal samples in the
entire room.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description=" - Put your choice description here -" resultScene="F.oak_room"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="H.fur_room">
        <description>The beams of the flashlights show a room filled with furs
covering the walls, ceiling, and floor. There is a large spiral staircase
in one corner that seems to be made out of metal.

The furs are purple in color and very rough to the touch. They do not appear to be dyed,
and each furis very large and cannot be cut or moved from any section of the
room. The spiral staircase is in the northwest corner of the room. It is
made of metal and painted with purple enamel paint. If paced out, the
room is eighty feet east and west and sixty feet wide to the north and
south.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description=" inspect furs on wall." resultScene="H.inspect_wall"/>
            <choice description="Go up the spiral staircase." resultScene="H.spiral_staircase"/>
            <choice description="Go back to the passageway." resultScene="G.passageway"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="H.inspect_wall">
        <description>If any tapping is done to the wall section marked with the secret door symbol it will
            show a hollow sound. If the wall is closely examined by hand, that whole section of
            fur will appear to be loose. It will easily move to the side with the push
            of a hand, revealing a normal door.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Go through the secret door." resultScene="I.statue_room"/>
            <choice description="Stay in fur room." resultScene="H.fur_room"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="H.spiral_staircase">
        <description> --- describe the scene here ---</description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
    <scene name="I.statue_room">
        <description>The beams of the flashlights show a room filled with statues of
differing types. The walls, floor and ceiling are of green paneled
wood.
There are fifteen statues in this area:
three Viking types with ring mail for armor, horned helmets, and
drawn swords in their hands; two female amazon types, each with a
bow and arrow ready to fire; four men in plate mail with plumed
helmets and swords at their sides; and five Wisconsin State Highway
Patrolmen with pistols and equipment on their belts and nightsticks in
their hands. The room is paced out to be sixty feet to the east and
west and forty feet to the north and south.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Attempt to speak with the statues" resultScene="I.talk_to_statues"/>
            <choice description="Attack the statues." resultScene="I.attack_statues"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="I.talk_to_statues">
        <description> They make some grunting noises back to you.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Attack the statues." resultScene="I.attack_statues"/>
            <choice description="Continue" resultScene="I.statue_room"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="I.attack_statues">
        <description> --- describe the scene here ---</description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
    <scene name="A.mirror">
        <description>You find that the mirror lifts easily. There is a secrete door behind it.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Try to open the secret door." resultScene="P.plant_room"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="P.plant_room">
        <description>The beams of the flashlights show a room filled with plants
from wall to wall and traveling up to the ceiling. One also notices a
strange purple glow from the bottoms of all the plants. An exit is
visible on the other side of the room.

All of the plants are in tanks that
are filled with a glowing purple liquid. The plants seem to sway
towards any people entering the area. Some of them bear fruit and
berries. The room cannot be paced out because of the plants, but the
path from exit to exit is eighty feet.

</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Inspect the plants" resultScene="P.inspect_plants"/>
            <choice description="Go back to foyer." resultScene="A.inside_entrance"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="P.inspect_plants">
        <description>Seven stirges fly out and attack. Their pointy beaks suck your blood.</description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
    <scene name="J.Bathroom">
        <description> The beams of the flashlights show a bathroom with all the
things one would expect to find in such a place. There is a sink with a
mirror above it, a stool, and a bathtub. The floor, walls, ceiling, and all
The water works fine in this area, except when it is about to overflow any sink or tub or stool for any
reason. It will cut itself off first. There are hinges on the door frame but
no other sign that there ever was a door there. If paced out the main
room is forty feet by forty feet, plus a hall section that has the tub at its
end. This hall section starts on the south wall and is ten feet wide
(east and west) and twenty feet long.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Examine the sink. Turn on water" resultScene="J.turnOnWater"/>
            <choice description="Open the medicine cabinet." resultScene="J.medicine_cabinet"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="J.medicine_cabinet">
        <description> The mirror over the sink has a recessed cabinet.
In it are two small plastic bottles of pills:
   One has ten green pills.
   One has twenty pink pills.
</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description=" - Put your choice description here -" resultScene="J.takeGreenPill"/>
            <choice description="Swallow one of the green pills." resultScene="J.takePinkPill"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="B.rat_attack">
        <description>Rats com out from under the couch and attack you.
One bites you and gives you a terrible disease.
(Suggestion: maybe we should have generated melee combat here so the outcome is random.)
        </description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
    <scene name="B.key">
        <description>
You find a golden key under the pile of leaves.
(Suggestion: keep an inventory of items that the player has.)
        </description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Continue" resultScene="B.rat_room"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="L.upStaircase">
        <description> The beams of the flashlights show a room covered in small
furs of some type and a spiral staircase leading up through the
ceiling.
 The fur seems to be rat fur. It has lice and smells of rotten meat.
It covers the walls, floor and ceiling and when cut it shows bare
cement floor and metal walls underneath. If the room is paced out,
it is sixty feet square. The staircase is made of metal and painted
with black enamel paint and is located in the northwest corner of the room.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="walk up the spiral staircase." resultScene="X.spiralStaircase"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="K.trophyRoom">
        <description>The beams of your flashlight show a large room with animal
heads hanging on the walls and large animals mounted fully on
stands. There are many of these all over the room. There are exits on
the east and west walls.
  This is a trophy room of some type with stuffed felines of all
different descriptions along the brown painted walls. On the north
wall is a cabinet with three long rifles that are very heavy, and two
shorter rifles that have two barrels apiece. There is a drawer under these rifles,
containing two boxes of what must be shells. Besides the triggers,
there are two levers on each gun; one is large and on the stock and one
is small and near the trigger.
   If paced out, the room is forty feet east and west and sixty feet north and south.</description>
        <choices>
            <choice description="Take one of the guns." resultScene="K.trophyRoom"/>
            <choice description="Proceed through the exit to the west." resultScene="L.upStaircase"/>
        </choices>
    </scene>
    <scene name="X.spiralStaircase">
        <description> The beams of the flashlights reveal a room covered in furs of
various types. There is also'an exit out of the area on a side wall.
The furs are all very thick and there are some recognizable ones including:
zebra, lion, leopard, and polar bear.
 Each fur is worth at least fifty gold pieces
and easily detachable from its mounting. When more than one
character walks onto the furs, the characters are attacked by four
giant centipedes (HP: 2,2,1,2; #AT: 1; 0: Nil; AC: 9; SA: Save versus
poison). These creatures are hidden under furs until movement
rouses them.</description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
    <scene name="VII.chunksRoom">
        <description> The beams of the flashlights show a room with a number of
metal chunks littering the floor. There are three doors, each one on a
different wall.
When you enter the room, metal chunks fall from the ceiling, and characters can see that the ceiling is
massed with millions of these chunks stuck to it.
 After a character or party enters
the room, every melee round 3-18 of these chunks will fall. They
weigh fifteen ounces each and do 1-6 points of damage when hitting
a player. There is only a 15% chance that any given one will hit, since
, they fall throughout the general area of the player. The doors are all
fake and while the handles will turn, they can't open. They appear to
be made from oak, but are metal like everything else.</description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
    <scene name="J.turnOnWater">
        <description>The water works fine in this area,
except when it is about to overflow any sink or tub or stool for any
reason. It will cut itself off first.</description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
    <scene name="J.takeGreenPill">
        <description>Everything around you seems to move in slow motion.
(time  sped up to twice normal for three melee rounds)
</description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
    <scene name="J.takePinkPill">
        <description>Healing.  Up to ten lost hit points per pill are restored.</description>
        <choices/>
    </scene>
</script>
